Remberto Villar

Queens, New York | (347) 279-8277 | rembertovillar@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby OOP, Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in Python. Possess strong collaborating team skills to ensure successful project design. Ultimately provide solutions that help drive positive results in building and deploying applications. Passionate about learning and strengthening my soft and hard skills, while staying current with technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Ruby, Rails, Active Record, Sinatra, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Material UI, React Bootstrap, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Lo-ki MCU - Github

A discussion forum, where users can search through the Marvel API for comic books of their preferred characters. The user can like and post comments, as well as perform CRUD actions.

- Developed a full stack web application with a rails backend, and React front end.
- Created validations to protect the integrity of the data being stored in the database.
- Incorporated authentication in the backend to store passwords securely using BCrypt password hashing algorithm.
- Followed the MVC pattern to organize the code, and OOP design patterns to set up the classes for the models.
- Put in place client-side routes implementing React router, a navigation bar that displays information based on whether a user is registered on the page.
- The UI was built with the Material UI library, for responsive user experience on both desktop and mobile.

Task-Master - Github

A note taking app, where the user can create, edit, delete and customize the notes.

- Built a React frontend application with the API to perform CRUD actions.
- Built Sinatra API backend that used Active Record to access and persist data in the SQL database.
- Used OOP design patterns in the Ruby programming language to create classes for each of the models.
- Incorporated Material UI framework to style the frontend application.

JRF Burger Shop - Github

A single page burger shop web application where a user can choose from selected burgers.

- Created client-side routes using React router, this included a navigation bar and other UI elements that allowed the user to navigate between routes.
- Used a json-server to create a RESTful API for the backend and make GET, POST and DELETE requests to the json server.

EXPERIENCE

New York-Presbyterian / Weill Cornell Medical Center Nurses Aid

New York, NY 01/2019 - Present

- Collaboration with clinical and administrative staff to ensure successful execution of the company's mission, vision and values.
- Provide excellent customer service and communicate any change in patient's behavior. Responsible for documenting patient's information and vitals into Epic database.

Google, Inc. New York, NY

Google's Mentorship and Development Program Mentee

11/2020 - 06/2021

- Was part of Google's CSSI: Online Program cohort, a 2-week intensive introductory project-based python processing curriculum taught by Google engineers. While in the program completed a series of labs to strengthen problem solving and critical thinking skills.
- Met 1:1 with Google engineers to develop personal and professional goals over a 6-month period.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

06/2022 - 10/2022

Queens College Queens. NY **B.S.** Computer Science 01/2022 - 01/2024

Queensborough Community College A.A.S. Computer Information Systems

Queens, NY 01/2020 - 12/2021